<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alireza Baloochi</title>
    <link>https://baloochi.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alireza Baloochi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://baloochi.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2020 Recap</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2021/01/2020-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2021/01/2020-recap/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if anyone is reading this but here goes nothing, 2020 was such an odd year (I guess for everyone). first of all, got my diploma in an odd state, after being informed at march that due to the severeness of this virus giving exams is almost impossible I was worried about the state of my education, also hearing that IB students gave no exams and got horrible results from IB representatives with their academic performance (somewhat randomized since everyone put effort on studying for finals rather than research topics) , it was tougher for us since the Iranian education ministry is more strict and offers no value for off-site exams and the Dubai Knowledge and Development Authority does not allow on-site exams (because they were responsible for students, totaly understandable).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Code-in</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2019/12/google-code-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2019/12/google-code-in/</guid>
      <description>The Journey It goes back all the way in November when Fedora Project tweeted that they need some Mentors for Google Code-in. Initially I didn&amp;rsquo;t knew what it was but after a simple search it was clear that it was a competition ran by Google.
So Google provided all the backend and platform for open source organizations, which mentors of each org then creates tasks in the system, which then the student solves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robocup Asia-Pacific @ Dubai</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2018/12/robocup-asia-pacific-dubai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2018/12/robocup-asia-pacific-dubai/</guid>
      <description>In December 1st we were told by our CS teacher that there will be a Robocup held in Dubai, I was really intrested and since the material they introduced was mostly graphical with some Arduino code in it, I decided to join although I had limited experience in both of these subjects. The school created a workshop + election process at friday, which consisted of using the code to run virtual robots in an area, which was powered by Microsoft Robotics suit and Nvidia PhysX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/about/</guid>
      <description>My Full CV: 📃 Curriculum Vitae.
If you wish to contact me, you can send a message on Telegram.
Works:  Mentor at Google Code-in 2019 System Administrator at Tehran Internet Co. Exhibitor at Dubai Knowledge and Human Development Authority Ranked 5th in the National Cyber Olympiad Fedora Project Contributor Certified Online Tutor and E-lecture Designer by HBMSU Fedora Open source Project Contributor Dubai Young City Makers participant  Intrests:  Swimming &amp;amp; biking Writing (Essay, Documentation) Coding &amp;amp; Designing Photography  Languages:  Persian (Native) English (Fluent) Arabic (Familiar) German (Familiar)  You can find more info about me in my Linkedin, I post updates there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photographs</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/photographs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/photographs/</guid>
      <description>Here you can see my shots, for obvious reasons they are heavily compressed here. 
Full Image gallery in 500px Tehran - Chitgar Park FiruzKuh - Zarindasht FiruzKuh - HableRud Dubai - DubaiMall</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
