<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alireza Baloochi</title>
    <link>https://baloochi.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alireza Baloochi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons Licence&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/80x15.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://baloochi.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Robocup Asia-Pacific @ Dubai</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2018/12/robocup-asia-pacific-dubai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2018/12/robocup-asia-pacific-dubai/</guid>
      <description>In December 1st we were told by our CS teacher that there will be a Robocup held in Dubai, I was really intrested and since the material they introduced was mostly graphical with some Arduino code in it, I decided to join although I had limited experience in both of these subjects. The school created a workshop + election process at friday, which consisted of using the code to run virtual robots in an area, which was powered by Microsoft Robotics suit and Nvidia PhysX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Works:  Mentor at Google Code-in 2019 System Administrator at Tehran Internet Co. Exhibitor at Dubai Knowledge and Human Development Authority Ranked 5th in the National Cyber Olympiad Fedora Project Contributor Certified Online Tutor and E-lecture Designer by HBMSU  Intrests:  Swimming &amp;amp; biking Writing (Essay, Documentation) Coding &amp;amp; Designing Photography  Languages:  Persian (Native) English (Fluent) Arabic (familiar) German (Familiar)  You can find more info about me in my Linkedin, I post updates there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photographs</title>
      <link>https://baloochi.me/photographs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://baloochi.me/photographs/</guid>
      <description>Here you can see my shots, for obvious reasons they are heavily compressed here. 
Full Image gallery in 500px Tehran - Chitgar Park FiruzKuh - Zarindasht FiruzKuh - HableRud Dubai - DubaiMall</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>