<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Alireza Baloochi</title>
        <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Alireza Baloochi</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://baloochi.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>2020 Recap</title>
            <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2021/01/2020-recap/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2021/01/2020-recap/</guid>
            <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if anyone is reading this but here goes nothing, 2020 was such an odd year (I guess for everyone). first of all, got my diploma in an odd state, after being informed at march that due to the severeness of this virus giving exams is almost impossible I was worried about the state of my education, also hearing that IB students gave no exams and got horrible results from IB representatives with their academic performance (somewhat randomized since everyone put effort on studying for finals rather than research topics) , it was tougher for us since the Iranian education ministry is more strict and offers no value for off-site exams and the Dubai Knowledge and Development Authority does not allow on-site exams (because they were responsible for students, totaly understandable).</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don&rsquo;t know if anyone is reading this but here goes nothing, 2020 was such an odd year (I guess for everyone). first of all, got my diploma in an odd state, after being informed at march that due to the severeness of this virus giving exams is almost impossible I was worried about the state of my education, also hearing that IB students gave no exams and got horrible results from IB representatives with their academic performance (somewhat randomized since everyone put effort on studying for finals rather than research topics) , it was tougher for us since the Iranian education ministry is more strict and offers no value for off-site exams and the Dubai Knowledge and Development Authority does not allow on-site exams (because they were responsible for students, totaly understandable).</p>
<p>Oh and is someone confusing why Dubai and the Iranian ministry are mentioned here, it&rsquo;s because I study in an Iranian school which is certified by both ministries, so they have to comply with both but it&rsquo;s good for us since we get 2 diplomas, 1 from Iranian ministry and 1 from Dubai knowledge Authority. You have 2 pass two extra courses to get the Dubai one, Islamic and UAE social studies. (UAE is a federal government, so each state has it&rsquo;s own education system.)</p>
<p>Then after a long 2 months, the UAE&rsquo;s ministry of education gave permission for the exams to be carried out but in a very protective manner, no public transportation should be used for students, parents should come and pick us up, social distancing, mask + shields and so on. No one was ready for this, and exams were crammed so it would end asap. (it was so horrible that we had 1 day to study physics.)</p>
<p>Anyways I got done with that and got my report card in july aaand I missed my deadline for college application, usually it would have ended by the end of August but covid said screw you! My average was 97% , kinda okay since I expected my exams to be harder.</p>
<p>-to be continued</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Google Code-in</title>
            <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2019/12/google-code-in/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2019/12/google-code-in/</guid>
            <description>The Journey It goes back all the way in November when Fedora Project tweeted that they need some Mentors for Google Code-in. Initially I didn&amp;rsquo;t knew what it was but after a simple search it was clear that it was a competition ran by Google.
So Google provided all the backend and platform for open source organizations, which mentors of each org then creates tasks in the system, which then the student solves.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/img/photo/codein.png" alt="main page" title="Main page"></p>
<h2 id="the-journey">The Journey</h2>
<p>It goes back all the way in November when Fedora Project tweeted that they need some Mentors for Google Code-in. Initially I didn&rsquo;t knew what it was but after a simple search it was clear that it was a competition ran by Google.<br>
<br>
So Google provided all the backend and platform for open source organizations, which mentors of each org then creates tasks in the system, which then the student solves. At the end students will be rewarded goodies all supplied by Google.<br>
<br>
<img src="/img/photo/codein2.jpg" alt="Short Description">
<br>
It was clear that Google wants to be viewed as open-source supporter and get some love from the students, then also hiring talented ones, so Google gets a big piece here. (Although Open-source orgs can show their stuff too but much less compared to Google)<br>
<br>
See some info <a href="https://opensource.google/community/">here</a></p>
<h2 id="getting-chosen">Getting chosen</h2>
<p>Well after filling the simple form I was contacted by Vipul, the event manager that I should hand some draft tasks for him to analyse so I kept working and used my Internship Knowledge to create some server tasks, which was accepted by Vipul and I was in.<br>
After a while we were given the link to register as mentor and deploy our tasks with markdown, everythign was straight forward and documented</p>
<p><img src="/img/photo/codein3.jpg" alt="My tasks"></p>
<h2 id="competition">Competition</h2>
<p>Initially Studnts grabbed and then abandoned my tasks, which I was told that this is regular because they are getting familiar with the UI.<br>
<br>
After reviewing some submissions I was worried that the tasks are way to easy, so I removed some Documentation tasks to minimize spams. Then Created LaTeX and NextCloud ones instead, which students loved.<br>
<br>
After a week the submission amount was enormus, I got 50 ish tasks to review everyday, it was convenient and boring at the same time.<br>
<br>
We had some conferences at the end to choose the winners with other mentors, and after announcing winners and runner-ups, the event was ended.<br>
<br>
The only student form my Area (UAE, Dubai) actually won the first place, but never went to the Google Headquarters because of the Covid-19 pandemic. (Believe me it is very sad.)</p>
<h2 id="what-i-got">What I got</h2>
<p><br>
<strong>My Goodies aren&rsquo;t shipped yet this is what we are &ldquo;supposed&rdquo; to get</strong><br>
<br>
<img src="https://prajwalpatiltech.files.wordpress.com/2017/02/img_20170222_161114-e1487761420101.jpg?w=775" alt="rewards"><br>
<br>
Well Physically: certificate and a T-shirt but the most important ones are friends and the experience which will top everything here.</p>
<p><a href="https://codein.withgoogle.com">check the website</a><br>
<a href="https://medium.com/@p4r4xor/my-journey-at-google-code-in-paraxor-8492c4b15eda">paraxor&rsquo;s awesome event description for students</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Robocup Asia-Pacific @ Dubai</title>
            <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2018/12/robocup-asia-pacific-dubai/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2018/12/robocup-asia-pacific-dubai/</guid>
            <description>In December 1st we were told by our CS teacher that there will be a Robocup held in Dubai, I was really intrested and since the material they introduced was mostly graphical with some Arduino code in it, I decided to join although I had limited experience in both of these subjects. The school created a workshop + election process at friday, which consisted of using the code to run virtual robots in an area, which was powered by Microsoft Robotics suit and Nvidia PhysX.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In December 1st we were told by our CS teacher that there will be a Robocup held in Dubai, I was really intrested and since the material they introduced
was mostly graphical with some Arduino code in it, I decided to join although I had limited experience in both of these subjects.
<br>
<br>
The school created a workshop + election process at friday, which consisted of using the code to run virtual robots in an area, which was powered by Microsoft Robotics suit and Nvidia PhysX. My team was elected to participate, since we have done the fastest lap by combining ultrasonic sensivity and follow the line sensors. (It was quite easy since we used a graphical user interface to program the virtual robots, which then translated into C++ code that the virtual bot executed.
<br>
<br>
You can see some useful info in <a href="http://robocupap.org/index.php/dubai2018/">Event Website</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6KHG87fK4LE">Event video</a>.
<br>
We won the election process and went for the master competition held in Dubai Knowledge village.
<br>
<br>
The beginning of the event was easy since it was quite similar to what our school trained us for but the final levels were quite hard as the code should both run on the Physical and Virtual robot which was quite scary as sometimes the one that worked on the virtual bot didn&rsquo;t work on physical and vice versa.
<br>
<br>
<img src="/img/photo/robo.jpg" alt="menu">
<br>
After lots of challenge our team <em>Pioneers</em> got the first place in U19 challenge which was quite nice, although we asked why the code gave different results on Physical and Virual, the company supplier told us that in order to make the virtual section more challenging they assigned some random values to initial velocity which gave weird results everytime in return. Some fine shots can be seen here:
<br>
<br>
<img src="/img/photo/robo2.jpg" alt="menu">
<br>
<br>
<img src="/img/photo/robo3.jpg" alt="menu"></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
