<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Alireza Baloochi</title>
        <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Alireza Baloochi</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons Licence&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://baloochi.me/img/cc.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://baloochi.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Robocup Asia-Pacific @ Dubai</title>
            <link>https://baloochi.me/posts/2018/12/robocup-asia-pacific-dubai/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://baloochi.me/posts/2018/12/robocup-asia-pacific-dubai/</guid>
            <description>In December 1st we were told by our CS teacher that there will be a Robocup held in Dubai, I was really intrested and since the material they introduced was mostly graphical with some Arduino code in it, I decided to join although I had limited experience in both of these subjects. The school created a workshop + election process at friday, which consisted of using the code to run virtual robots in an area, which was powered by Microsoft Robotics suit and Nvidia PhysX.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In December 1st we were told by our CS teacher that there will be a Robocup held in Dubai, I was really intrested and since the material they introduced
was mostly graphical with some Arduino code in it, I decided to join although I had limited experience in both of these subjects.
<br>
<br>
The school created a workshop + election process at friday, which consisted of using the code to run virtual robots in an area, which was powered by Microsoft Robotics suit and Nvidia PhysX. My team was elected to participate, since we have done the fastest lap by combining ultrasonic sensivity and follow the line sensors. (It was quite easy since we used a graphical user interface to program the virtual robots, which then translated into C++ code that the virtual bot executed.
<br>
<br>
You can see some useful info in <a href="http://robocupap.org/index.php/dubai2018/">Event Website</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6KHG87fK4LE">Event video</a>.
<br>
We won the election process and went for the master competition held in Dubai Knowledge village.
<br>
<br>
The beginning of the event was easy since it was quite similar to what our school trained us for but the final levels were quite hard as the code should both run on the Physical and Virtual robot which was quite scary as sometimes the one that worked on the virtual bot didn&rsquo;t work on physical and vice versa.
<br>
<br>
<img src="/img/photo/robo.jpg" alt="menu">
<br>
After lots of challenge our team <em>Pioneers</em> got the first place in U19 challenge which was quite nice, although we asked why the code gave different results on Physical and Virual, the company supplier told us that in order to make the virtual section more challenging they assigned some random values to initial velocity which gave weird results everytime in return. Some fine shots can be seen here:
<br>
<br>
<img src="/img/photo/robo2.jpg" alt="menu">
<br>
<br>
<img src="/img/photo/robo3.jpg" alt="menu"></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
